A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Annual Reports to the President, 1958-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Annual Reports to the President 1958-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/1.841
This collection consists of 87 vol.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1984 February 21.
Biographical/Historical Information
After 1972, scattered copies of individual reports may be found in the office administrative files of the President's Office and the office of the Vice-President and Provost or in the records of the individual school or department.
Scope and Content Information
Reports submitted to the President each year by each of the schools and departments in the University. Topics covered in the reports include enrollment, curriculum, publications and research, staff, budgets, honors and distinctions, reports on individual students, immediate and long-term needs, and recommendations.
The early volumes occasionally contain tipped-in letters received by President Edwin A. Alderman regarding the quality of various programs at the University. Included at various times are reports submitted by the University Librarian, the Dean of the Academic Faculty, the Curator of the University of Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (Bayly Museum), the directors of Blandy Farm, Mountain Lake and Seward Forest, the deans of the Extension Division and the Summer Quarter and the Secretary of the University (the Registrar in later years), whose report includes figures on student enrollment, geographical distribution, church membership, age, and degrees.
At times the reports are marked as having been initially submitted to the Dean of the College.
Contents List
- All Schools/Departments in one binder 1958-1959 (Box 1)
- Medicine/Nursing 1959-1960 (Box 2)
- College of Arts and Sciences (includes individual departments) 1959-1960 (Box 2)
- Includes all but College of Arts and Sciences, Medicine, and Nursing (includes Architecture, Blandy Farm, et. al.) 1950-1960 (Box 3)
- Includes all except Medicine, Nursing, College of Arts and Sciences, Graduate Arts and Sciences (includes Admissions, Architecture, et. al.) 1960-1961 (Box 4)
- College of Arts and Sciences, Graduate Arts and Sciences (includes individual departments) 1960-1961 (Box 4)
- Medicine/Nursing 1960-1961 (Box 5)
- Education/Engineering/Extension/Law/Public Relations/Seward Forest/Summer Session/Virginia Quarterly Review 1961-1962 (Box 5)
- Faculty of Arts and Sciences (includes individual departments)/Graduate Arts and Sciences 1961-1962 (Box 5)
- Medicine/Nursing 1961-1962 (Box 6)
- Includes all except Medicine/Nursing/Faculty Art and Sciences/Graduate Arts and Sciences (includes Admissions, Architecture, et. al.) 1961-1962 (Box 6)
- Medicine/Nursing 1962-1963 (Box 6)
- Admissions/Architecture/Athletics, et. al. 1962-1963 (Box 7)
- Education/Summer Session/Engineering and Applied Science/General Studies/Law/Public Relations/Virginia Quarterly Review 1962-1963 (Box 7)
- College of Arts and Sciences (includes individual departments)/Graduate Arts and Sciences 1962-1963 (Box 8)
- Admissions/Architecture, et. al. 1963-1964 (Box 8)
- Medicine/Nursing 1963-1964 (Box 9)
- College of Arts and Sciences/Graduate Arts and Sciences (includes individual departments) 1963-1964 (Box 9)
- Education/Summer Session/Engineering and Applied Science/General Studies/Institutional Analysis/Law/Public Relations/Virginia Quarterly Review 1963-1964 (Box 10)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1964-1965 (Box 10)
- Admissions/Athletics, et. al. 1964-1965 (Box 10)
- Library 1964-1965 (Box 11)
- Comptroller/Dean of the University, et. al. 1964-1965 (Box 11)
- General Studies/Law 1964-1965 (Box 11)
- Faculty of Arts and Sciences (all departments) 1964-1965 (Box 12)
- Medicine/Nursing 1964-1965 (Box 12)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1965-1966 (Box 13)
- General Studies/Law 1965-1966 (Box 13)
- Library 1965-1966 (Box 13)
- Admissions/Athletics, et. al. 1965-1966 (Box 13)
- Arts & Sciences (includes individual departments) 1965-1966 (Box 14)
- Comptroller/Dean of the University, et. al. 1965-1966 (Box 14)
- Medicine/Nursing 1965-1966 (Box 15)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1966 (Box 15)
- Medicine/Nursing 1966 (Box 15)
- Arts & Sciences 1966 (Box 16)
- General Studies/Law 1966 (Box 16)
- Admissions/Athletics, et. al. 1966 (Box 16)
- Library 1966 (Box 17)
- Comptroller/Dean of the University, et. al. 1966 (Box 17)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1967 (Box 17)
- General Studies/Law 1967 (Box 18)
- Admissions/Athletics, et. al. 1967 (Box 18)
- Arts & Sciences 1967 (Box 18)
- Medicine/Nursing 1967, 2 folders (Box 19)
- Library 1967 (Box 19)
- Comptroller/Planning, et. al. 1967 (Box 19)
- General Studies/Law 1968 (Box 20)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1968 (Box 20)
- Comptroller/Planning Department, et. al. 1968 (Box 20)
- Arts & Sciences 1968 (Box 21)
- Medicine/Nursing 1968 (Box 21)
- Admissions/Athletics, et. al. 1968 (Box 22)
- General Studies/Law 1969 (Box 22)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1969 (Box 22)
- Comptroller/Vice President for Student Affairs, et. al. 1969 (Box 23)
- Arts & Sciences, A-G 1969 (Box 23)
- Arts & Sciences, H-Z 1969 (Box 24)
- Admissions/Athletics, et. al. 1969 (Box 24)
- Medicine (Part I) 1969 (Box 24)
- Medicine (Part II)/School of Nursing 1969 (Box 25)
- Architecture/Graduate Business Administration, et. al. 1970 (Box 25)
- Admissions/Athletics, et. al. 1970 (Box 26)
- Vice President for Student Affairs, et. al. 1970 (Box 26)
- Arts & Sciences, A-G 1970 (Box 26)
- Arts & Sciences, H-Z 1970 (Box 27)
- General Studies/Law 1970 (Box 27)
- Scholarly Publications/School of Medicine 1970 (Box 27)
- General Studies 1970-1971 (Box 27)
- Law 1970-1971 (Box 28)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1971 (Box 28)
- Arts & Sciences, A-G 1971 (Box 28)
- Arts & Sciences, H-Z 1971 (Box 29)
- Medicine 1971 (Box 29)
- Admissions, et. al. 1971 (Box 30)
- Library 1971 (Box 30)
- Vice President for Business and Finance/Vice President for Student Affairs 1971 (Box 30)
- Nursing 1971 (Box 30)
- Summary of 1971 Annual Reports 1971 (Box 30)
- Medicine 1971-1972 (Box 31)
- Engineering and Applied Science 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 31)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1972 (Box 32)
- Arts & Sciences, Art through Humanistic Sources 1972 (Box 32)
- Arts & Sciences, Mathematics through Washington Papers 1972 (Box 33)
- Miscellaneous 1972 (Box 33)
- Medicine (Part I) 1972-1973 (Box 33)
- Medicine (Part II) 1972-1973 (Box 34)
- Medicine, Equal Opportunity Report 1972-1973 (Box 34)
- Nursing 1972-1973 (Box 34)
- Continuing Education 1972-1973 (Box 34)
- Doris Wilsdorf (University Professor) 1972-1973 (Box 34)
- Library 1972-1973 (Box 35)
- Engineering and Applied Science 1972-1973 (Box 35)
- Architecture/Business Administration, et. al. 1973-1974 (Box 35)
- Arts & Sciences, A-F 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 35)
- Arts & Sciences, G-Z 1973-1974, 3 folders (Box 36)
- Committees/Centers of Research, et. al. 1973-1974 (Box 36)
- Parking and Transit/Dean of Student Affairs, et. al. 1973-1974 (Box 36)
- Engineering and Applied Science 1973-1974 (Box 37)
- Miscellaneous - U.Va. Library/Nursing (Incomplete) 1973-1974 (Box 37)
- Miscellaneous - Annual Reports/Budget Requests, etc. 1974 (Box 37)